Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
The Resettlement Administration (RA) section contains extensive fieldnotes, correspondence, memoranda and reports for the remaining field trips that Cowell made during her tenure at the RA, beginning around the autumn of 1936, through 1937, when the Resettlement Administration was reorganized under the Farm Security Administration (FSA). The RA was a New Deal program designed to provide economic aid to struggling rural, and to a lesser extent urban, families during the Great Depression. Cowell explained in a letter that the RA was using the native music of these rural communities as an agent of socialization and cooperation. She recorded extensively in the Ozarks, the Appalachians, and the Great Lakes Region during her time with the RA. Under the FSA, she served as regional representative and relief community manager in the Great Lakes Region for much of 1937. The material included in this subseries reveals Cowell’s sensitive and perceptive prose that offers insights into the communities in which she was living and working. The correspondence, memos, and reports to her RA colleagues, including Adrian Dornbush, Robert Van Hyning, and Grete Franke, illuminate behind-the-scenes problems, issues, and relationships within the RA on almost a weekly basis.
The California Folk Music Project (CFMP) section contains materials relating to Cowell’s most innovative and ambitious project. The CFMP was a New Deal collecting project that Cowell conceived of and managed for the Northern California Work Projects Administration. It was one of the earliest major attempts at documenting traditional and ethnic music in a specific region. Material in the section includes the final report for the project, in addition to notes and an outline for a book on folksong in California that she never completed. Extensive lists of recordings she made of traditional English-language, Western European, and Hispanic ethnic music contain date and place of recording, performer name, and annotations by Cowell.
The Carrie Grover from Gorham, Maine section contains a list of songs by Grover that Cowell recorded in 1941. The Appalachian Trip with Maud Karpeles section contains Cowell’s handwritten diary and notes from the 1950 trip to Appalachia during which she and Karpeles re-recorded performers originally recorded from 1916 to 1918 by English folksong collector Cecil Sharp. A list of the recordings also is included.
The Wolf River Songs and Ford-Walker Family section documents Cowell’s ongoing work with the music-making Ford-Walker family of Wisconsin. The material contains notes and drafts for the Folkways publication Wolf River Songs as well as annotated song sheets and lists of the Anglo-Irish ballads and lumber camp songs that she collected from the family.
The Songs from Cape Breton Island section contains handwritten drafts and annotated song sheets and transcriptions for her Folkways publication Songs from Cape Breton Island. Correspondence sheds light on preparations for the recording trip to Nova Scotia. The material also includes transcriptions of songs recorded by the North Shore Singers during that time and on other occasions.
The Songs of Aran section contains annotated song sheets and transcriptions from Cowell’s 1955 recording trip to Inishmore, the largest of Ireland’s Aran Islands. Cowell used this material in producing Songs of Aran for Folkways.
In the mid-1950s, Sidney Robertson Cowell and her husband Henry Cowell travelled extensively in Asia and the Middle East for both the State Department and the Rockefeller Foundation to lecture, assess grant requests, and report on the status of classical and traditional music in various countries. Sidney Robertson Cowell took the opportunity to record many of the traditional musicians she encountered during these trips. The Travels in Asia and Middle East section contains notes, drafts, and finished reports written by Cowell detailing their activities and describing an area’s music and culture.
The Materials Relating to Henry Cowell series consists of a variety of materials, including correspondence, narratives, articles, and music holographs that are either by or about Henry Cowell. Henry Cowell permeates practically the entire Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection, but it was deemed necessary to create a separate series to accommodate the large amount of material related directly to him. It is divided into three sections. The Miscellaneous Material by and about Henry Cowell section contains narratives written by Sidney Robertson Cowell in later years about various aspects of Cowell’s life and work. In addition, there are essays and articles on music written by Henry Cowell, items relating to his discography, as well as commemorative articles on Cowell written for various occasions. This section also includes materials related to his two stepmothers. The “Henry by Sidney” section contains draft material for a biography of her husband that Sidney Robertson Cowell never completed. In her later years, she recorded onto tape personal and professional reminiscences about Henry Cowell and their life together which she planned to turn into a book. The transcriptions of those tapes are included here with Sidney Robertson Cowell’s notes and annotations. The Music by Henry Cowell section contains a small group of photocopies of musical holographs by Henry Cowell that are held in the Library of Congress.
Of particular interest in the Biographical Material series are narratives and essays written by Sidney Robertson Cowell in the 1970s that offer a revealing look back on her career and life with Henry Cowell. The series also contains a travel diary, notes, anecdotes, and random thoughts about her work, travels, and life in general. This series also includes clippings and articles about Cowell and reviews of her work, in addition to detailed family histories and documents relating to her ancestors from the Morrison-Tonnelle (mother’s side) and Hawkins (father’s side) families. One can also find her diploma, passports, and drawings in this series.
The Writings and Publications series offers a rich trove of Cowell’s writings, many in various stages of creation, from handwritten notes and annotated drafts to finished published products. Some items contain annotations that Robertson Cowell made long after the item was published. The series is divided into three sections. The Published Writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell section consists of her major publications as well as reviews, articles and obituaries of Percy Grainger and Charles Seeger. It also contains three items that were attributed to Henry Cowell, but were actually written by Sidney. Of particular interest in the Unpublished Writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell section is the part containing her Narratives on Collecting, which are revealing and lively accounts of past collecting and recording activities written in the 1980s and 1990s. The Drafts of Reviews, Papers, and Reports part contains drafts for many of the pieces found in the Published Writings section. Of particular interest are several drafts for an unfinished piece called “Three Generations of Folk Singers in the United States” and a draft for an article entitled “Music in Ghana” that was never published. The Miscellaneous part includes items such as project proposals, notes from courses, and fiction and poetry. The third section, Publications Written by Others, contains books, journals, and reports dealing primarily with folklore and traditional and world music. Explanatory narratives by Sidney Robertson Cowell accompany Midsummernight by Carl Wilhelmson and her Farsi primer.
The Subject Files series contains an assortment of materials related to people, organizations, and topics that figured prominently in Cowell’s personal and professional life. There is a significant amount of material (correspondence, articles, narratives and clippings) related to Charles Ives, about whom Sidney and Henry Cowell wrote a highly-respected book entitled Charles Ives and his Music. In addition, there is correspondence, accompanied by related notes, drafts, and essays, with individuals such as Bruce Saylor, Stephen Spackman, and James Ross, asking for advice, discussing writing projects, or consulting on issues related to Henry Cowell. There is background material related to music festivals and conferences in which Sidney Robertson Cowell took a major role. This series also includes material dealing with Cowell’s teaching career and some items relating to the Pan American Union where she worked in the early 1940s, including copies of Recordings of Latin American Songs and Dances: An Annotated Selected List of Popular and Folk Music by Gustavo Duran and edited by Sidney Robertson Cowell.
The Photographs series consists mostly of black and white photographs of Sidney Robertson Cowell; Henry Cowell; their families; and various friends, colleagues, and associates. Photography was Sidney Robertson Cowell’s avocation and she took many of the photographs found in this series. Folk and ethnic music performers that Cowell recorded throughout her career are the subjects of numerous photographs. Photographs of the offices and staff of the California Folk Music Project are included here as well as photographs of nature scenes, landscapes, abstracts, and animals taken by Sidney Robertson Cowell.
The Teaching Materials series contains notes, outlines, song sheets, reports, and narratives related to Cowell’s music classes for children and for a course on rhythm that she taught at the New School.
The Songs and Song Books series contains lists and books of songs that were collected by Sidney Robertson Cowell throughout her career. Of particular interest is a collection of folk songs with piano settings by Henry Cowell. This series also contains a collection of protest and propaganda songs from the 1930s and 1940s and a collection of songs sung by Cinderella Kinnaird, whom Cowell recorded.
Organization of the Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection
The Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection is organized into nine series:
Correspondence
Materials Relating to Fieldwork
Materials Relating to Henry Cowell
Biographical Material
Writings and Publications
Subject Files
Photographs
Teaching Materials
Songs and Song Books
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006560750
Container List
- Correspondence, 1908-1988, bulk 1920-1979 (Box 1-5)
  - Personal (non-family) and Professional, 1913-1988 (Box 1-4)
    Correspondence to and from friends, acquaintances, colleagues, associates, businesses and organizations relating to personal and professional activities. May include material attached to letters. Correspondents who are identified by first name only, or are unidentified, are placed at the end of the subseries. Correspondence from a particular individual or organization to Cowell are filed together with items from Cowell to that person or organization.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization and chronologically therein.
    - Adams, Ansel, 1964-1965, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Adams, Ansel, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Ambron, Emilio, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Amirkhanian, Charles, 1981, 1986 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Arma, Paul, 1980 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Asch, Moe, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Avrich, Paul, 1979, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1960-1981, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Bacon, Ernst, 1975 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Bloch, Suzanne, 1967, 1983, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Bowen, Carroll “Curley,” 1968 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Bronson, Bertrand, 1977-1980 see also Container 21, Harvard University see also Container 21, Ives, Charles (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Broun, Heywood Hale, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Brown, Frank C. see Container 6, Correspondence, 1936
    - “B” miscellaneous, 1914-1981 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Cage, John, 1968, 1982-1987, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Castro, Gloria, 1977 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - C.G. Jung-Institut (Zürich, Switzerland) see Hannah, Barbara
    - Claflin, Avery, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Claflin, Jock, 1979 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Clay, Carleton, 1987 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Corry, Mary Jane, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Cowell, Henry see Container 4
    - Cronin, Patrick see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Cunningham, Merce, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Cuomo, Mario, 1986-1987 see also New York Times (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Curtiss, Mina, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - “C” miscellaneous, 1928-1988 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Da Capo Press see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - Daniel, Oliver, 1968, 1973 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Davies, Dennis Russell, 1978 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Duveneck, Frank see Duveneck, Josephine
    - Duveneck, Josephine, 1974-1978, undated (Box-folder 1/28)
    - “D” miscellaneous, 1979-1988, undated (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Echols, Paul C., 1976 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Edinger, Dora, undated (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Elise, Mother, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Elkus, Albert, 1942, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Elkus, Jonathan see Elkus, Albert
    - Eskin, Sam, 1974-1979, undated see also Goodhue, Cornelia “Connie” see also Greer, Lucia C. (Chia) see also Resnick, Nat (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Eskin, Stanley see Eskin, Sam
    - Etchepareborde, Felix (SRC’s mother’s houseman), 1939 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Fassett, Stephen see Container 21, Hayes, Roland
    - Feder, Stuart, 1977 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Findley, Jannelle Warren- see Warren-Findley, Jannelle
    - Fitzgibbon, Liam see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Fleming, Shirley see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - Ford, Warde, 1954 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Forgostein, Harold E. see Temple of the People
    - Foss, Lukas, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Fowler, William H. Begbie (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Frankel, Max see New York Times
    - Frankenstein, Alfred, 1974-1979, undated (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Friedland, Bea see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - Garland, Peter, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Gbeho, Philip see Container 21, Africa
    - Goldman, Daniel Franko, 1984 (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Goldman, Richard Franko, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Goodhue, Cornelia “Connie,” 1974 see also Eskin, Sam (Box-folder 1/44)
    - Grainger, Ella, 1968 (Box-folder 1/45)
    - Grainger, Percy, 1950-1955 see also Manville, Stewart (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Greer, Lucia C. (Chia), 1976 see also Eskin, Sam (Box-folder 1/47)
    - “G” miscellaneous, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 1/48)
    - Hannah, Barbara, 1977 (Box-folder 1/49)
    - Harlem School of the Arts, 1969-1979, 1985 see also Rooks, Shelby (Box-folder 1/50)
    - Harootunian, Hollis see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - Harris, Leonard R. see New York Times
    - Harrison, Lou, 1947-1979 (Box-folder 1/51)
    - Harrison, Lou, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 1/52)
    - Harrison, Lou, undated (Box-folder 1/53)
    - Harvard University see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Hawkins, Erick, 1984 (Box-folder 1/54)
    - Hayes, Afrika see Container 21, Hayes, Roland
    - Henahan, Donald see New York Times
    - Herron, Eileen Curran see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Higgins, Dick see Container 21, Cage, John
    - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 1/55)
    - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 1/56)
    - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1981-1987, undated see also Container 21, Ives, Charles (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Hood, Mantle, 1978 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Hulme, Kathryn see Container 21, Hulme, Kathryn
    - Humphrey, Hubert, 1977 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - “H” miscellaneous, 1958, 1968, 1976-1977, undated (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Institute for the Study of American Music see Hitchcock, H. Wiley
    - International Folk Music Council, undated (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Ives, Harmony, 1964 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Jackson, Richard, 1981 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Jellinek, George, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1943, 1952, 1986, undated (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Karas, Josef “Joza” M., 1985 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Karpeles, Maud, 1961 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Kershaw, Maureen, 1978-1988, undated (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Kikuzawa, James (family cook), 1940-1941, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - King, Terry, 1982 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Kirkpatrick, John, 1974-1976, undated see also Container 21, Ives, Charles (Box-folder 2/15)
    - “K” miscellaneous, 1957, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Leavitt, Donald, 1985 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Libove, Charles, 1972, undated (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Lichtenwanger, William, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Lichtenwanger, William, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Lichtenwanger, William, 1985-1986, undated see also Container 22, Saylor, Bruce (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Linsley, Ralph, 1979-1980, undated (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Lomax, John, 1936 see also Container 6, Correspondence, 1936 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Luening, Otto, 1936, 1958, 1975 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Lugovoy, Nina see Libove, Charles
    - “L” miscellaneous, 1957-1961, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - MacLeod, Malcolm Angus see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Maizner, Helen see WBAI Radio
    - Mandel, Nancy Siegmeister and Alan, 1973 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Manion, Martha, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Manville, Stewart, 1975, 1978 see also Grainger, Percy (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Maynor, Dorothy see Harlem School of the Arts
    - Mazzeo, Rosario see Adams, Ansel
    - McCann, Gordon, 1988 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - McKinney, Eleanor see WBAI Radio
    - McPhee, Colin, 1962-1964, undated, Letters about Colin McPhee. Correspondents include Margaret Mead, Oliver Daniel and Mantle Hood. (Box-folder 2/30)
    - McPhee, Colin, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - McPhee, Colin, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - McPhee, Colin, undated (Box-folder 2/33-39)
    - Mead, Rita, 1976, 1978, 1983 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Mennin, Peter, 1975 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1983 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Miller, Philip Lieson, 1981 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - M.I.T. Press see Bowen, Carroll “Curley”
    - Moore, Douglas see Container 21, Columbia University
    - Mother Elise see Elise, Mother
    - Musical America see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - “M” miscellaneous, 1945, 1964, 1975, 1983-1988, undated (Box-folder 3/5)
    - New York Public Library see Jackson, Richard
    - New York Times, 1979-1985, undated see also Container 1, Cuomo, Mario (Box-folder 3/6)
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1951, 1971, 1978 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Oppens, Ursula, 1984-1986, undated (Box-folder 3/8)
    - O’Reilly, F. Warren, 1973 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Oxford University Press see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1965, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Packard, Emmy Lou, 1956, 1965 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Parsons, William, 1981 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Payne, C. Robert and Jane, 1975-1979, undated (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Pazmor, Radiana, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Perlis, Vivian, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Podesta, Evelyn Wells see Wells, Evelyn
    - Powell, Laurence, 1974 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Prabha, Chun, 1958 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - “P” miscellaneous, 1943, 1959, 1968, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Rasiej, Maria see Container 21, Hulme, Kathryn
    - Ray, Nicholas see Container 6, Correspondence, fieldnotes, 1937 May-June
    - Resnick, Nat, 1975 see also Container 1, Eskin, Sam (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Reston, James see New York Times
    - Ritchie, Jean see Container 21, Columbia University
    - Rooks, Shelby, 1960-1964, 1977 see also Harlem School of the Arts see also Container 21, Hayes, Roland (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Roosevelt, James, 1978 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Rorem, Ned, 1979 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Rosenfield, Lib and Milton, 1972 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Ross, James see Container 22, Ross, James
    - Rossiter, Frank R., 1974 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - “R” miscellaneous, 1974-1977, 1985, undated (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Sadie, Stanley, 1976 see also Saylor, Bruce (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Saylor, Bruce, 1974-1979 see also Sadie, Stanley see also Container 22, Saylor, Bruce (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Schickele, Peter, 1986 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Schuman, William, 1977 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Seeger, Charles, 1940, 1959-1973 see also Container 6, Correspondence, 1936 see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, notes, 1936 Jan.-Oct. see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, field reports, 1936 Nov. see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, fieldnotes, 1936, Nov. 21-23 see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1936, Nov. 27-Dec. 30 see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, 1937 Jan.-Feb. see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1937 July-Sept. see also Container 6, Correspondence, memoranda, 1938 Jan., undated see also Container 22, Pan American Union (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Seeger, Peggy, 1976, 1985, undated (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Seeger, Pete, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Shumway, Eleanor M. see Temple of the People
    - Sicade, Sally, 1940 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Silver, Brian, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Slattery, Thomas C., 1968 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1985 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Spackman, Stephen see Container 22, Spackman, Stephen
    - Stevens, Denis, 1980 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Stone, Kurt, 1974 (Box-folder 3/38)
    - “S” miscellaneous, 1969, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 3/39)
    - Temple of the People, 1985 (Box-folder 3/40)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1953-1954, 1976-1979, 1985-1987, undated see also Container 21, East-West Music Encounter Union (Box-folder 3/41)
    - Tuckwell, Barry, 1976 (Box-folder 3/42)
    - Tureck, Rosalyn, 1981 (Box-folder 3/43)
    - Turnbull, Pete, 1958, 1979, undated (Box-folder 3/44)
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1954, 1974-1984, undated (Box-folder 3/45)
    - Valiant, Margaret, 1946, 1979, undated (Box-folder 3/46)
    - “V” miscellaneous, 1965, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 3/47)
    - Walton, Marion, 1964-1968, undated (Box-folder 3/48)
    - Warren-Findley, Jannelle, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 3/49)
    - WBAI Radio, 1966, 1973 (Box-folder 3/50)
    - Weisgall, Hugo, 1966, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/51)
    - Wells, Evelyn, 1947, 1962-1963, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 3/52)
    - Weschler, Lawrence see Container 21, Ives, Charles
    - White, Lynn, 1955 (Box-folder 3/53)
    - Whitney, Elizabeth G., 1940 (Box-folder 3/54)
    - Williams, Brent see Container 21, Hayes, Roland
    - Wilson, Dwight, undated (Box-folder 3/55)
    - Wolff, Leona, 1975 (Box-folder 3/56)
    - Wood, Robert C. see Container 21, Harvard University
    - Wyner, Yehudi, 1978, 1986, undated (Box-folder 3/57)
    - Wyss, Niklaus, 1975 (Box-folder 3/58)
    - “W” miscellaneous, 1953, 1961-1969, 1972-1976, 1986 (Box-folder 3/59)
    - Yates, Peter, 1966, 1978 (Box-folder 3/60)
    - Yuize, Shin’ichi, 1978-1980 see also Container 21, East-West Music Encounter (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Zulueta, Jorge, 1973 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Letters identified by first name, A-G (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Letters identified by first name, J-L (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Letters identified by first name, M-T (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Unidentified, 1913, [1924?], 1954 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Fragments of letters (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Family, 1908-1988 (Box 4-5)
    Correspondence to and from husbands, parents, siblings, in-laws and other family members relating to personal and professional activities. May include material attached to letters. Family members identified by first name only and correspondence addressed to “family” are placed at the end of the subseries. Correspondence both to and from Cowell and a particular individual are usually filed together within each folder. It will be noted when correspondence is separated.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person and chronologically therein.